

Jay Shitesh da Silva

Student

Personalia

Address

Egelantierstraat 24b 3073VK, Rotterdam Netherlands

Phone

0623186886

Email

shitesh.da-silva@outlook.com

Date of birth

29-08-2004

Proficiencies

Programming Languages: C#, Python, SQL, TypeScript

Frontend Development: ReactJS, HTML, JSON

Backend and Tools: Git, RESTful API, SQLite, CI/CD Workflows, .NET Entity Framework

Other Skills: Scrum, Kanban, Unit-Integration Testing, GitHub (Actions / Secrets)

Skills

Ability to work in a team

Eager to learn

Analytical insight

Languages

English, Dutch

• • • • •

Profile

Enthusiastic Computer Science student passionate about technology and software. My background in Business Administration gives me a unique perspective on integrating technical solutions into business strategies. I combine my studies with work experience in various roles, which has led to strong skills in teamwork, problem-solving, and customer orientation. Thanks to my diverse experience, I quickly integrate into new work environments and efficiently acquire new skills.

Education

Computer Science, Rotterdam University of Applied Sciences

Sep 2023 – Present Wijnhaven 107, 3011 WN Rotterdam

I am a second-year Computer Science student at Rotterdam University of Applied Sciences, where I further develop my skills in software development and information technology. I have obtained my propedeuse in Computer Science and have knowledge in both frontend and backend development, including, Python, C#, TypeScript, ReactJS, SQL.

Business Administration, Erasmus University Rotterdam

I partially studied Business Administration at Erasmus University Rotterdam before switching to Computer Science, realizing that it better matched my interests in technology and IT.

VWO Economics & Society, Calvijn Zuider Gymnasium

Graduated from Zuider Gymnasium in Rotterdam. Obtained my VWO diploma with a focus on Economics & Society. Additionally, I studied business economics and general economics.

Projects

Office Calender - Event Management System

(React, TypeScript, ASP.NET Core, RESTful API, C#, SQLite)

For this web development project, I developed an Event Management System with a React and TypeScript frontend and a C# and ASP.NET Core backend. Users can manage, attend, and review events through an intuitive interface. The system utilizes an SQLite database and demonstrates proficiency in API integration, user authentication, and session management.

CargoHub - Logistics Management System

(Python, SQL, Unit-Integration tests, JSON, CI/CD, GitHub Actions)

In this project, I was given legacy code from an old logistics management system that no longer functioned. Using **unit and integration tests**, and **endpoint testing**, I identified and resolved the issues. Additionally, I migrated the **JSON database** to **SQL** and wrote

performance tests for optimization. For Continuous Integration, I used GitHub Actions and Dependabot to manage automated tests and updates. This project strengthened my skills in problem-solving, software testing, database management, and CI/CD workflows.

Shinema - Cinema Management System

(C#, JSON, Software testing, OODP)

For the Shinema project, I developed an application for managing a cinema. The system provides features for handling movies, reservations, seat management, and user accounts via a **terminal-based user interface (UI)**. The application follows a **three-layer architecture**, consisting of a **presentation**, **logic**, **and data layer**, and was developed with **C# and JSON**. This project enhanced my skills in **object-oriented programming and software design**.

Certificates

Propaedeutic Diploma in Computer Science

Aug 2023 — Jul 2024 Rotterdam University of Applied Sciences

Successfully completed with **60 study credits** in the first year of the bachelor's program, deepening my knowledge in **Python**, **C#**, **SQL**, and tools like **Git**.

Pre-Academic Programme

Sep 2022 − Jul 2023

© Erasmus University Rotterdam

Completed a program focused on academic skills and a successful transition into higher education.

Employment History

Cinema Service Employee, Pathé

Oct 2024 – Present © Cor Kieboomplein 501, 3077MK Rotterdam

As a cinema employee, I ensure a pleasant customer experience. I am responsible for various tasks, from ticket sales and assisting guests as a host to preparing the screening rooms as an usher. I quickly resolve customer inquiries and work within the ushering team to get rooms ready under time pressure. This requires strong planning, communication, and teamwork.

Flower Delivery Driver, Spargle

Apr 2024 — Jul 2024 Seinhuiswachter 2, 3034 KH Rotterdam

As a flower delivery driver at Sparqle, I was responsible for efficiently and timely delivering flowers for a florist/distributor.

Kitchen Assistant, Euromast Restaurant

Feb 2024 - Mar 2024 Parkhaven 20, 3016 GM Rotterdam

As a kitchen assistant at Euromast, I supported the kitchen team in dishwashing and logistics, including loading and unloading carts.

Warehouse Employee, Nespresso Boutique

As a warehouse employee at Nespresso Boutique, I was responsible for efficiently managing stock and processing orders.